Guide to the Jane Hood Collection of Video Oral Histories of New England Area Leaders of the Communist Party of the United States TAM.655
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Jane Hood Collection of Video Oral Histories of New England Area Leaders of the Communist Party of the United States
1980s
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Hood, Jane C.
Stange, Eric, 1953-
Buhle, Paul, 1944-
TAM.655
4.5 Linear Feet in 4 record cartons, and 1 audio box
15 interviews on 74 videocassettes
82 videodisc (dvd) in 1 audio box
The Jane Hood Collection of Video Oral Histories of New England Area Leaders of the Communist Party of the United States (dates 1980s) is composed of interviews with members of the New England Communist Party and children of New England Communists. Oral history interviews in this collection were created in the 1980s by Eric Stange and Paul Buhle for various oral history projects. They were later used by Jane Hood in preparation for a book about her own experience as the daughter of an American Communist. The collection consists of 15 interviews on 74 U-matic tapes. The recordings generally relate to the experiences of American Communists during the Cold War, but details about the topics addressed in individual interviews are unclear.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Jane Hood in 2014. The accession number associated with this collection is 2014.165.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by interviewee last name.
Historical
Oral history interviews in this collection were created in the 1980s for several different oral history projects. A portion of the videos were created by Eric Stange for his 1989 documentary Children of the Left. Other interviews were recorded by historian Paul Buhle. They were later used by Jane Hood in preparation for a book about her experience growing up in a Communist household. Hood's father, Otis Hood, was the Chairman of the Massachusetts Communist Party in the 1950s.
Custodial History
A portion of the video oral histories in this collection were created by Eric Stange. Other interviews were created by historian Paul Buhle. Videos were later given to Jane Hood by Eric Stange.
Scope and Contents
The Jane Hood Collection of Video Oral Histories of New England Area Leaders of the Communist Party of the United States (dated 1980s) is composed of interviews with members of the New England Communist Party and children of New England Communists. The collection consists of interviews with 15 individuals on 74 U-matic tapes. The recordings generally relate to the experiences of American Communists during the Cold War, but details about the topics addressed in individual interviews are unclear. Interviews with Jane Hood, Richard Healey, and Joan Sokoloff also feature their mothers Fran Hood, Dorothy Healey, and Edith Abber. In other cases the names of interviewees are unclear. Recordings include a mixture of masters and dubs, as well several tapes containing still images and background footage.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Oral histories (literary works); Communists -- United States -- Interviews.; Communism and families -- United States.; Families -- Political aspects -- United States.; New England; Communist Party of the United States of America
- Chernin, Kim, undated; cuid103 (Box 1, Video 103A-G, Box 5, Dvd 103A-G)
- Chorover, 1985 November 29; cuid104 (Box 1, Video 104A-E, Box 5, Dvd 104A-E)
- Felsen, undated; cuid105 (Box 1, Video 105A-E, Box 5, Dvd 105A-E)
- Ford, Glenn, undated; cuid106 (Box 2, Video 106A-D, Box 5, Dvd 106A-D)
- Franklin, undated; cuid107 (Box 2, Video 107A-C, Box 5, Dvd 107A-C)
- Healey, Richard, undated; cuid108 (Box 2, Video 108A-F, Box 5, Dvd 108A-F)
- Hood, Jane and Fran Hood, 1986 April 22; cuid109 (Box 3, Video 109A-H, Box 5, Dvd 109A-H)
- Horowitz, David, undated; cuid110 (Box 3, Video 110A-J, Box 5, Dvd 110A-H, 110J)
  Scope and Contents
  Item 110i was duplicate of 110j and was not transferred
- Khan, Tony, 1986 January 9; cuid111 (Box 4, Video 111A-D, Box 5, Dvd 111A-D)
- McDonald, "Country" Joe, undated; cuid112 (Box 2, Video 112A-E, Box 5, Dvd 112A-E)
  A portion of the interview with Country Joe McDonald featured on access copy 112E contains content from the interview with Franklin. The portion featuring McDonald occurs in the last 10 minutes of the recording.
- [Rubenstein], Gilda, 1986 May 28; cuid113 (Box 4, Video 113A-F, Box 5, Dvd 113A-F)
- Shapiro, Lynn, 1986 December; cuid114 (Box 4, Video 114A-D, Box 5, Dvd 114A-D)
- Sokoloff, Joan and Edith Abber, 1981 May; cuid115 (Box 4, Video 115A-G, Box 5, Dvd 115A, 115C-G)